CURRICULUM VITAE

K.N. SRIKANTH

MECHANICAL ENGINEER (HVAC, FIRE FIGHTING SYSTEM & PLUMBING)

Mobile no: +918179652334

Email: srikanth.mech320@gmail.com

Skype ID:srikanth kudupudi



Summary:

Graduate in mechanical engineering (B.Tech) with over 8 years experience (5 years in saudi arabia and 3 years in india) in the field of design, Estimation & Execution of HVAC ,Plumbing & fire fighting system of Residential ,commercial and Industrial projects.

Professional Experience:

Company : DOHA UNIQUE UNIVERSAL LLC, Saudi Arabia (5- years)

Period: Febraury 2013 - March 2018

Designation: Project Engineer

Major Projects:

- 1. Student affairs Building (KFUPM @ Dharan) B+G+5 Store building, plot area:25,000 M².
- 2. Ashok Leyland work shop for Western Auto company at Dammam Area, plot area:960 M².
- 3. Pepsico Food Production Plant at Dammam 2nd industrial area.
- 4. SADARA, Central Analytical Laboratory -L4101 at Jubail.
- 5. Extension Of Kanoo Chemical Warehouse at Dammam seaport area.
- 6. Tenaris Saudi Arabia Ltd automotive supplier plant at Dammam 2nd industrial area.
- 7. 3M project at Dammam 3rd Industrial area.

Responsibilities:

- Prepare and maintain the Material Submittal flow sheet.
- Obtain quotations from suppliers. Evaluate offers and prepare comparative statements.
- Check and prepare material submittals in conjuction with the project manager.
- Prepare and maintain the shop drawings flow sheet.
- Review comments received from the consultant on material submittals and shop drawings. Prepare and organizere-submittals as required.
- Take-off material quantities from the approved drawings and prepare material requisitions.
- Ensure that all materials are ordered in time so that the progress on site is not interrupted or delayed.
- Plan labor requirements based on the construction program and provide requirements to the project manager.
- Prepare regular progress reports and submit to the project manager.
- Attend scheduled meetings as advised by the project manager with other parties i.e client, consultant & main contractor.
- Plan, prepare the document for testing and commissioning and supervise all related commissioning activities.
- Rectify and complete snags prior to final handover.
- Responsible for mentoring, guiding and evaulation foremen and supervisory staff.

- Responsible for ,in co-ordination with the foremen and supervisory ,work allocation and execution on a daily basis.
- Review and monitor montly labor performance and utalization against the planned targets.

➤ Company : SP ENTERPRISES, Berhampur –odisha (1- year)

Period: December 2011 - February 2013

Designation : Site Engineer Major Projects: IOCL paradip

Responsibilities:

• Work profile is to scheduling the work ,tracking the material requirement for the fabrication and coordinate with the consultant as well.

- Take-off material quantities from the approved drawings and prepare material requisitions.
- Plan & prepare the document for QA/QC and supervise all related activities.
- Prepare regular progress reports and submit to the project manager.
- Monitoring and tracking of the tools and tackle used for fabrication work.
- To organize monthly programmer for achieving the target.

Company : ASN IndustriesPvt Ltd,Katni –MP (2- year)

Period: November 2009 – November 2011

Designation: Site Engineer

Major Projects: 7.5 MW coal based power project.

Responsibilities:

- Site management and handling of work as per drawing.
- Monitoring progress of work as per schedule.
- Control of the quality at site as per requirement.
- Co-ordination with sub-contractor and suppliers departement.

Experience summary:-----

- 5 years in (HVAC, FIRE FIGHTING SYSTEM & PLUMBING) execution experience.
 - 2 years in power projects execution.
 - 1 year in structural steel fabrication.

- ____ _Excellent in using carrier HAP software. _____ _________________________
 - Excellent in MS office.
 - Familiar with MEP REVIT & Autocad.

Key skills:

***** HVAC:

Cooling & Heating Load Calculation:

General & E-20 manual calculation, Ventilation and Infiltration Load Calculation, Winter load calculation Ventilation System Designing, Fresh Air Handling Unit Designing as per ASHRAE 62.1., Restaurant/Residence kitchen ventilation system designing as per ASHRAE 90.1, Non-Central and Central Toilet Exhaust Calculations as per ASHRAE 62.1., Car Parking Ventilation system Designing(Impulse & Induction Fan System), Design of Stairwell Pressurization System, ,Transformer Room ventilation, Generator Room ventilation requirements.

SOFTWARE DESIGNING:

Cooling and Heating Load calculation using Hourly Analysis Programme (HAP), Calculation of duct sizes by McQuay Duct sizer, Calculation of Chilled water pipe sizes by McQuay pipe Software, Air terminal selection by using BETA Programme, VRV Equipment Selection by TOSHIBA Software.

HVAC DRAFTING:

Representation of Concepts Design Drawing, Design Drawing & Shop Drawing, Preparation of Detail Shop Drawing of Air-Conditioning & Ventilation Ducts, Chilled Water Pipes & Duct Fittings-Elbows, TEE's,. & Duct Support, Representation of Duct Pipe Levels, Slope, flow direction, BOD's, BOP's,.

♦ Plumbing:

DESIGN CALCULATION:

Domestic Water Tank, Overhead tank Sizing, Cold Water Pipe Sizing in Building as per flow rate and fixture Unit Method(WFU), Booster pump sizing & transfer, Pump Sizing (HP & Watts).

Hot Water System Designing, Estimating Hot Water Demand, Calculating the Capacity of Non-Central & Central Water Heaters, Hot Water Pipe Sizing, Hot Water Circulating Pump Design.

Soil and Waste water drain calculation in building vertical stack, Branch drain / Discharge pipe, horizontal drain, Fixture unit rating, Maximum number of discharge unit allowed in stack, Design of horizontal drains by discharge unit method(DFU), Invert level & Slope calculation, Sump Pit Sizing, Submersible Sump Pump Sizing, Design of Septic tank, Soakaway pits.

Designing of Storm water Drainage system in building, Sizing of Rain Water Gutters.

DRAFTING: Representation of Concepts Design Drawing, Design Drawing & Shop Drawing.

Qualification:

- **B.Tech** in **Mechanical Engineering** (2005-2009) from B.V.C.Engeering College, ODALAREVU, Affiliated by JNTU, with 57.6%.
- Intermediate from C.D.P.Jr.College, AMALAPURAM, with 73.0%.
- S.S.CfromKENNEDYCONVENTHIGH SCHOOL, NARANDARAPURAM with 70.0%.

Personal details:

Date of Birth : June 10, 1988

Marital Status : Married

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Telugu*

Contact details : k.pedapudi, kudupudivaripalem,

ambajipeta Mandal, pin-533239,

East Godavari District, A.P, India.

I certify that the information furnished above is true, complete and correct, to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Thanking You

K.naga srikanth.